<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Mackenzie Morgan</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/</link><description>This is my cool site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 07:48:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mackenzie.morgan.name/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>See you in New York</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/see-you-in-new-york/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 07:48:48 -0400</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/see-you-in-new-york/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://codebeamnyc.com/#schedule" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">schedule for Code BEAM Lite NYC</a> has been posted, and I&rsquo;m on it. I will be the first talk after the keynote, so that&rsquo;s exciting! I&rsquo;ll be doing a new talk this time, on adapting how you think about algorithms when shifting from an imperative programming mindset to a functional programming mindset.</p>
<p>This&rsquo;ll be my third time speaking at a Code BEAM event. Relatedly, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eMt_Wwp3N70" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">recording of my talk in Mexico City</a> has finally been uploaded to YouTube. Code BEAM recordings tend to be posted shortly before the following conference of a similar type (ie, that was a Code BEAM Lite and this is a Code BEAM Lite), probably to build excitement for the next one. Unfortunately, the audio isn&rsquo;t great, but if you want to hear what I sounded like doing public speaking <em>in Spanish</em> a year and a half ago, there you go. In the Spanish version, I took into account feedback from when I did it in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-hcvGTwPLFI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">2022 in English</a>, adding a more substantial introduction.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Heading to Pycon 2024</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/heading-to-pycon-2024/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 18:04:17 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/heading-to-pycon-2024/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://us.python.org/2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">PyCon US</a> is going to be in my hometown this year! I don&rsquo;t live there anymore, but it&rsquo;ll be a nice chance to spend a weekend in downtown Pittsburgh, sort of playing tourist. (I think we can all guess that visiting my parents in the suburbs is nothing like &ldquo;playing tourist,&rdquo; right?)</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m looking forward to getting to see one of my coworkers again. I met him last year at the Code BEAM Lite Mexico City, and he said he&rsquo;s going to be bringing his mom to PyCon this year. I made them a list of touristy things to do in Pittsburgh. The one problem with remote work is that I rarely get to see my coworkers. I like the balance where some companies have annual off-sites, but I don&rsquo;t work at one of those. I&rsquo;ve only met my coworkers by means of personal travel.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Queer Tango Festival</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/queer-tango-festival/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 16:44:01 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/queer-tango-festival/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This past weekend I went to Miami for the <a href="https://miamiqueertangofestival.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Conexión International Queer Tango Festival</a>, and I had a blast!</p>
<p>Due to tornadoes in Florida, my flight was delayed, so I missed the opening performance, but I made it to the opening night milonga (dance party) and met some new friends there.</p>
<p>Friday, I really overdid it. I took like 5 dance classes and then went to that night&rsquo;s milonga and stayed until I don&rsquo;t know what time at night. In any case, walking down the hostel stairs the next day for breakfast was painful. I decided to have a more relaxed Saturday; I took a musicality class, went to the beach, came back for a panel discussion, then had dinner and a cortadito before that night&rsquo;s milonga. That cortadito was very helpful since they decided to keep the milonga going until 3am instead of the scheduled 1:30.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>2023 Summary: Part 5</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-5/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>At the end of <a href="/posts/2023-summary-part-4" rel="">part 4</a>, I said I&rsquo;d decided to round off my world travel by visiting my colleagues in Argentina.</p>
<h2 id="buenos-aires">Buenos Aires</h2>
<p>I spent the week before Thanksgiving in Buenos Aires. Finally, my spouse got to come along on one of these trips.</p>
<p>We learned you should not arrive in Buenos Aires on a Sunday. Nothing is open. No, you can&rsquo;t buy a sube (metro card) to ride the subte (metro). No, you can&rsquo;t go to Western Union to convert your dollars to pesos. You want to eat breakfast? There are two restaurants within 4 blocks that open before noon. But the weather was lovely, so we spent the morning sitting in various parks, enjoying it, and marveling at the telecoms cables draped from building to building.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>2023 Summary: Part 4</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-4/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="dance">Dance</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve never been one to dance at weddings. I was fine dancing ballet as a kid because I was told the order of steps to do. And at SCA events, I&rsquo;d participate in the medieval English country dance. Again, there was a sequence of steps to memorize. But improvisational dance? That was not me.</p>
<p>I decided it was time to get out of my shell and learn how to dance without a script.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>2023 Summary: Part 3</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-3/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>When I left off in <a href="/posts/2023-summary-part-2" rel="">part 2</a>, I said I spent July circumnavigating the globe. Also, I mentioned that I had started studying Swahili.</p>
<h2 id="kenya">Kenya</h2>
<h3 id="nairobi">Nairobi</h3>
<p>My group of Quakers (<a href="https://bym-rsf.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Baltimore Yearly Meeting</a>)   is associated with both <a href="https://www.fgcquaker.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Friends General Conference</a> (more liberal, no pastors) and <a href="https://fum.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Friends United Meeting</a> (often more conservative, usually pastors). Every 3 years, FUM has their triennial. Ok, that&rsquo;s obvious in the name. Anyway, the largest group of FUM Quakers is in Kenya, and it was their turn to host. I arrived a day early and met up with one of the other Baltimore folks for a visit to the Giraffe Centre.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>2023 Summary: Part 2</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In May, I went up to Pittsburgh for Mothers&rsquo; Day weekend. My brother&rsquo;s New Zealand work visa had come through, so he was saying goodbye to the family.</p>
<h2 id="exam-results">Exam results</h2>
<p>In June, I got the notification that I had passed my <a href="https://www.dele.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">DELE exam</a>. Woot!</p>
<p>The breakdown on scoring is a maximum of 25 points each for reading comprehension, writing skill, listening comprehension, and vocal interaction. You need 30 points total between reading and writing and again between listening and speaking.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>2023 Summary: Part 1</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-1/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s the end of December, and I&rsquo;ve barely blogged this year, so I&rsquo;m going to do a wrap-up for the year. 2023 was an <strong>extremely</strong> full year. There was an absolute <strong>ton</strong> of travel and a lot of being usefully bilingual.</p>
<p>There was so much stuff that I&rsquo;m splitting this into <strong>5 parts</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="belgium">Belgium</h2>
<p>At the beginning of February, I went to Belgium to speak in the Elixir/Erlang track at FOSDEM. My friend Nelson was also speaking on that track, and so our mutual friends Pablo and Diego came up from Spain to attend the conference too. We all stayed in the same hotel and stuck together the whole time. We introduced Pablo and Diego to Ethiopian food (Nelson had already tried it with me when visiting DC last year), and we all went to the only Cuban restaurant in Belgium our last night there. After explaining to the Spanish guys what <em>we</em> think of when we hear the word &ldquo;tamal&rdquo; (corn meal, with a stuffing, wrapped in a leaf), Nelson and I were very surprised to learn about tamal en cazuela, which is a casserole: no stuffing, and no leaf. It was tasty, though! Speaking Spanish even came in handy in Belgium in the &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t speak French, you don&rsquo;t speak English, any chance we both speak Spanish? Oh good!&rdquo; way.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Things your Spanish teacher didn't tell you</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/things-your-spanish-teacher-didnt-tell-you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 22:54:19 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/things-your-spanish-teacher-didnt-tell-you/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>A friend of mine (a native Spanish speaker) just started teaching one of his friends Spanish, and the first thing I said was:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Explain to her that ser is essence/identity/characteristic and estar is status, and that’ll go SO much better than the “ser is permanent and estar is temporary” that makes us try to say “es muerto” and “estoy bautista” (because hey, conversion exists). Like, death is pretty permanent, but it’s still a status.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Bulk Delete Twitter Messages</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/bulk-delete-twitter-messages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 23:43:37 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/bulk-delete-twitter-messages/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Hey, are you leaving Twitter? Are you worried that with 80% of the staff gone, it&rsquo;s just a matter of time until there start being unreported breaches? (Heck, maybe there have already!) Want to ensure anyone breaking into your account doesn&rsquo;t read your messages? Have a bulk-delete script, on the house!</p>
<p>To use this, go to <a href="https://twitter.com/messages" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">the messages page</a> on a computer. Right click somewhere on the page, and choose &ldquo;inspect&rdquo; (Chrome) or &ldquo;inspect element&rdquo; (Firefox) to get the developer tools to come up. (If you&rsquo;ve never seen that before, welcome to how so many of us learned to do things on the web!) In there, go to the tab labeled &ldquo;Console.&rdquo; Paste the following in and hit the enter or return key:</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>