<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>elixir - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/elixir/</link><description>elixir - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 21:09:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/elixir/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advent of Code 2021</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/advent-of-code-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 21:09:29 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/advent-of-code-2021/</guid><description><![CDATA[In general, I regard myself as pretty bad at algorithms. I&rsquo;m comfortable enough doing the Elixir track on Exercism (that&rsquo;s how I learned Elixir), and I&rsquo;ve used HackerRank some, but the reason I used HackerRank was because TripleByte said algorithms were my weak point. (It said architecture was my strong suit, and I&rsquo;m quite pleased with that, as I did put effort into improving on that front.) I really dislike white boarding in job interviews (both because of the nerves factor and because the problems are usually totally unrelated to the job) and so much prefer take-homes.]]></description></item><item><title>Pretty Waterfalls in Honeycomb</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/pretty-waterfalls-in-honeycomb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 10:14:01 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/pretty-waterfalls-in-honeycomb/</guid><description>When first setting up the Absinthe app I work on, someone added OpenCensus Honeycomb package. The way it was set up was very basic: each top-level query had tracing attached.
:object queries do field :getStuff, :stuff do meta :trace, true arg :input, :string resolve &amp;amp;Resolver.stuff_resolver/3 end end This got us information on how long each query took, so we could see which query needed to be optimized and do some debugging when performance issues hit.</description></item><item><title>Elixir Wizards Talk: "Dealing With a Monster Ecto Query"</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/elixir-wizards-talk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:27:31 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/elixir-wizards-talk/</guid><description>Last month, I spoke at the first-ever Elixir Wizards Conference. It was a lightning talk walking through a refactor I did before the 2020 US Presidential Election, titled &amp;ldquo;Dealing With a Monster Ecto Query.&amp;rdquo;
I work for a news company, so the presidential election is a huge deal; we can&amp;rsquo;t have downtime. I knew which query was our bottleneck, so I optimized it right before the election. This took advantage of a few Elixir features, like atoms, the pin operator, and concurrency primitives.</description></item><item><title>Start of a List</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/start-of-a-list/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 22:16:01 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/start-of-a-list/</guid><description>Elixir has a lot of ways to get the first thing in a list. One of the first things you learn from the basic syntax guide on the Elixir website is that hd(foo) gets the first thing in a list, and tl(foo) gets the rest. You also learn [ head | tail ] = foo.
But what happens when it&amp;rsquo;s an empty list?
iex(1)&amp;gt; foo = [] [] iex(2)&amp;gt; hd(foo) ** (ArgumentError) argument error :erlang.</description></item><item><title>Dang, Elixir is stable</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/dang-elixir-is-stable/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 21:12:59 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/dang-elixir-is-stable/</guid><description>On Monday, my manager asked about on-call coverage for the Elixir app I work on. There are only a handful of people in the company who know Elixir, and he was concerned that I would feel like I couldn&amp;rsquo;t take a vacation.
Him: How often do you get on-call alerts?
Me: shrug Never 😏
Him: Wait, what? Do you have them set up? Do they work? 😰
Me: Yeah, they&amp;rsquo;re set up, and yes, they work, but the interval&amp;hellip;Two weeks ago, another team made a change that affected us without telling us, and that caused an alert.</description></item><item><title>Attending Code BEAM</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/attending-code-beam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:39:55 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/attending-code-beam/</guid><description><![CDATA[Last week, Miriam Pena from the Erlang Ecosystem Foundation&rsquo;s education working group mentioned in the Elixir Slack&rsquo;s channel for women and other minority genders that Code BEAM V America was coming up. She said the working group had a handful of tickets available for students, folks who can&rsquo;t otherwise afford to go, and people in groups that are underrepresented in tech.
I&rsquo;ve never applied for a &ldquo;diversity&rdquo; ticket to a conference before, but she said they&rsquo;d pre-purchased them, and the conference was 6 days away.]]></description></item></channel></rss>