<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Tango - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/tango/</link><description>Tango - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 16:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/tango/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2023 Summary: Part 5</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-5/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>At the end of <a href="/posts/2023-summary-part-4" rel="">part 4</a>, I said I&rsquo;d decided to round off my world travel by visiting my colleagues in Argentina.</p>
<h2 id="buenos-aires">Buenos Aires</h2>
<p>I spent the week before Thanksgiving in Buenos Aires. Finally, my spouse got to come along on one of these trips.</p>
<p>We learned you should not arrive in Buenos Aires on a Sunday. Nothing is open. No, you can&rsquo;t buy a sube (metro card) to ride the subte (metro). No, you can&rsquo;t go to Western Union to convert your dollars to pesos. You want to eat breakfast? There are two restaurants within 4 blocks that open before noon. But the weather was lovely, so we spent the morning sitting in various parks, enjoying it, and marveling at the telecoms cables draped from building to building.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>2023 Summary: Part 4</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-4/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="dance">Dance</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve never been one to dance at weddings. I was fine dancing ballet as a kid because I was told the order of steps to do. And at SCA events, I&rsquo;d participate in the medieval English country dance. Again, there was a sequence of steps to memorize. But improvisational dance? That was not me.</p>
<p>I decided it was time to get out of my shell and learn how to dance without a script.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>