<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Career - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/career/</link><description>Career - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 10:54:40 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/career/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How's the Gender Ratio?</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/hows-the-gender-ratio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 10:54:40 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/hows-the-gender-ratio/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I recently completed a job hunt. I was a lot more intentional this time about having a list of questions to ask the companies I was interviewing with. I highly recommend <a href="https://www.keyvalues.com/culture-queries" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Key Values</a> for generating a list of questions to ask. They explain <em>why</em> they&rsquo;re worded the way they are, too.</p>
<p>I did ask one thing in a way they didn&rsquo;t suggest, though. Diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI) is a hot topic, and I know that asking specifically with those words is likely to get me a canned answer. I wanted to avoid that. And of course, I can look at a company&rsquo;s &ldquo;About Us&rdquo; page on their website and scroll through their LinkedIn results to get a sense of their gender and racial diversity.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>How to Network</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/how-to-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 04:39:51 +0000</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/how-to-network/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Maybe you&rsquo;re about to graduate, just graduated, or have been teaching yourself to code for the last few years, and you don&rsquo;t know how to get your foot in the door with that first job. You see all those &ldquo;entry-level&rdquo; jobs that expect a year or three of experience. Networking is incredibly important, especially if you don&rsquo;t have any professional experience in the tech industry yet.</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ve all heard it: &ldquo;it&rsquo;s not what you know; it&rsquo;s who you know.&rdquo; I, personally, have gotten only two jobs (in a 14-year career) from a cold start. And frankly, one wasn&rsquo;t a true cold start; a recruiter asked if he could show my 2017 resume to the company where I&rsquo;d done my first internship, way back in 2007.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>