<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>racism - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/racism/</link><description>racism - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 09:19:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/racism/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quakers &amp; Forced Assimilation of Native Americans</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/quakers-forced-assimilation-native-americans/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 09:19:28 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/quakers-forced-assimilation-native-americans/</guid><description>Quakers were heavily involved in the forced-assimilation of Native Americans.
Today, through the Friends Committee on National Legislation (the Quaker lobbyist), we advocate for Native rights and Native sovereignty. FCNL employs Portia Kay^nthos Skenandore-Wheelock, a member of the Oneida Nation to run its Native American Congressional Advocacy Program. It was previously run by Kerri Colfer of the Tlingit Nation, and before that Lacina Tangnaqudo Onco of the Shinnecock &amp;amp; Kiowa Nations.</description></item><item><title>Reading List: Quakers and Race</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/reading-list-quakers-race/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 14:39:55 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/reading-list-quakers-race/</guid><description>North American Quakers&amp;rsquo; history with racism is often whitewashed. Here are some links for a fuller picture.
Slavery in the Quaker World Quaker Indian Boarding Schools Fit for Freedom, Not for Friendship</description></item><item><title>A Vision of Racism and the Cross</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/vision-racism-the-cross/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 13:08:39 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/vision-racism-the-cross/</guid><description>Background This message was shared at West Hills Friends Church on 7 June 2020, as protests continued following the killing of George Floyd by police. It was presented over Zoom, due to the COVID-19 pandemic. This traveling ministry was undertaken under the care of Baltimore Yearly Meeting of the Religious Society of Friends. Scripture A reading from the Gospel of Matthew, chapter 25, verses 31 through 46.</description></item></channel></rss>