<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Conference - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/conference/</link><description>Conference - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 07:48:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/conference/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>See you in New York</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/see-you-in-new-york/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 07:48:48 -0400</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/see-you-in-new-york/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://codebeamnyc.com/#schedule" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">schedule for Code BEAM Lite NYC</a> has been posted, and I&rsquo;m on it. I will be the first talk after the keynote, so that&rsquo;s exciting! I&rsquo;ll be doing a new talk this time, on adapting how you think about algorithms when shifting from an imperative programming mindset to a functional programming mindset.</p>
<p>This&rsquo;ll be my third time speaking at a Code BEAM event. Relatedly, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eMt_Wwp3N70" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">recording of my talk in Mexico City</a> has finally been uploaded to YouTube. Code BEAM recordings tend to be posted shortly before the following conference of a similar type (ie, that was a Code BEAM Lite and this is a Code BEAM Lite), probably to build excitement for the next one. Unfortunately, the audio isn&rsquo;t great, but if you want to hear what I sounded like doing public speaking <em>in Spanish</em> a year and a half ago, there you go. In the Spanish version, I took into account feedback from when I did it in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-hcvGTwPLFI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">2022 in English</a>, adding a more substantial introduction.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Heading to Pycon 2024</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/heading-to-pycon-2024/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 18:04:17 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/heading-to-pycon-2024/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://us.python.org/2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">PyCon US</a> is going to be in my hometown this year! I don&rsquo;t live there anymore, but it&rsquo;ll be a nice chance to spend a weekend in downtown Pittsburgh, sort of playing tourist. (I think we can all guess that visiting my parents in the suburbs is nothing like &ldquo;playing tourist,&rdquo; right?)</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m looking forward to getting to see one of my coworkers again. I met him last year at the Code BEAM Lite Mexico City, and he said he&rsquo;s going to be bringing his mom to PyCon this year. I made them a list of touristy things to do in Pittsburgh. The one problem with remote work is that I rarely get to see my coworkers. I like the balance where some companies have annual off-sites, but I don&rsquo;t work at one of those. I&rsquo;ve only met my coworkers by means of personal travel.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Elixir Wizards Talk: "Dealing With a Monster Ecto Query"</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/elixir-wizards-talk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:27:31 -0400</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/elixir-wizards-talk/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Last month, I spoke at the first-ever <a href="https://smartlogic.io/about/community/elixir-wizards-conference/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Elixir Wizards Conference</a>. It was a lightning talk walking through a refactor I did before the 2020 US Presidential Election, titled &ldquo;Dealing With a Monster Ecto Query.&rdquo;</p>
<p>I work for a news company, so the presidential election is a huge deal; we can&rsquo;t have downtime. I knew which query was our bottleneck, so I optimized it right before the election. This took advantage of a few Elixir features, like atoms, the pin operator, and concurrency primitives.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Attending Code BEAM</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/attending-code-beam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:39:55 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/attending-code-beam/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Last week, <a href="https://github.com/miriampena" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Miriam Pena</a> from the <a href="https://erlef.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Erlang Ecosystem Foundation</a>&rsquo;s education working group mentioned in the <a href="https://elixir-lang.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Elixir</a> Slack&rsquo;s channel for women and other minority genders that <a href="http://codesync.global/conferences/code-beam-v-america-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Code BEAM V America</a> was coming up. She said the working group had a handful of tickets available for students, folks who can&rsquo;t otherwise afford to go, and people in groups that are underrepresented in tech.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve never applied for a &ldquo;diversity&rdquo; ticket to a conference before, but she said they&rsquo;d pre-purchased them, and the conference was 6 days away. Also, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-nVgAcy9wB0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">2020 Elixir survey results</a> say the community is 2% women, which is rather like the open source numbers back when I started doing that. (I hope the open source numbers have grown?) So, I figured it was probably ok to claim one.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>