<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - Mackenzie Morgan</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/</link><description>All Posts | Mackenzie Morgan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 21:12:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dang, Elixir is stable</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/dang-elixir-is-stable/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 21:12:59 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/dang-elixir-is-stable/</guid><description>On Monday, my manager asked about on-call coverage for the Elixir app I work on. There are only a handful of people in the company who know Elixir, and he was concerned that I would feel like I couldn&amp;rsquo;t take a vacation.
Him: How often do you get on-call alerts?
Me: shrug Never 😏
Him: Wait, what? Do you have them set up? Do they work? 😰
Me: Yeah, they&amp;rsquo;re set up, and yes, they work, but the interval&amp;hellip;Two weeks ago, another team made a change that affected us without telling us, and that caused an alert.</description></item><item><title>Attending Code BEAM</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/attending-code-beam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:39:55 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/attending-code-beam/</guid><description><![CDATA[Last week, Miriam Pena from the Erlang Ecosystem Foundation&rsquo;s education working group mentioned in the Elixir Slack&rsquo;s channel for women and other minority genders that Code BEAM V America was coming up. She said the working group had a handful of tickets available for students, folks who can&rsquo;t otherwise afford to go, and people in groups that are underrepresented in tech.
I&rsquo;ve never applied for a &ldquo;diversity&rdquo; ticket to a conference before, but she said they&rsquo;d pre-purchased them, and the conference was 6 days away.]]></description></item><item><title>Django Admin color picker</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/django-admin-color-picker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 03:09:31 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/django-admin-color-picker/</guid><description><![CDATA[When I add a new model to the Django app at work, I try to make sure the results in the Django admin have good usability, too. Just because it&rsquo;ll be mainly developers (and a few project managers) seeing it doesn&rsquo;t mean I can neglect usability. Consequently, I spend some time on hacking the Django admin. My manager says I&rsquo;ve been making it do things he didn&rsquo;t even realize were possible.]]></description></item><item><title>A Vision of Racism and the Cross</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/vision-racism-the-cross/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 13:08:39 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/vision-racism-the-cross/</guid><description>Background This message was shared at West Hills Friends Church on 7 June 2020, as protests continued following the killing of George Floyd by police. It was presented over Zoom, due to the COVID-19 pandemic. This traveling ministry was undertaken under the care of Baltimore Yearly Meeting of the Religious Society of Friends. Scripture A reading from the Gospel of Matthew, chapter 25, verses 31 through 46.</description></item></channel></rss>