<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - Mackenzie Morgan</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/</link><description>All Posts | Mackenzie Morgan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2023 Summary: Part 1</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-1/</guid><description><![CDATA[It&rsquo;s the end of December, and I&rsquo;ve barely blogged this year, so I&rsquo;m going to do a wrap-up for the year. 2023 was an extremely full year. There was an absolute ton of travel and a lot of being usefully bilingual.
There was so much stuff that I&rsquo;m splitting this into 5 parts.
Belgium At the beginning of February, I went to Belgium to speak in the Elixir/Erlang track at FOSDEM.]]></description></item><item><title>2023 Summary: Part 5</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-5/</guid><description>At the end of part 4, I said I&amp;rsquo;d decided to round off my world travel by visiting my colleagues in Argentina.
Buenos Aires I spent the week before Thanksgiving in Buenos Aires. Finally, my spouse got to come along on one of these trips.
We learned you should not arrive in Buenos Aires on a Sunday. Nothing is open. No, you can&amp;rsquo;t buy a sube (metro card) to ride the subte (metro).</description></item><item><title>2023 Summary: Part 4</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-4/</guid><description>Dance I&amp;rsquo;ve never been one to dance at weddings. I was fine dancing ballet as a kid because I was told the order of steps to do. And at SCA events, I&amp;rsquo;d participate in the medieval English country dance. Again, there was a sequence of steps to memorize. But improvisational dance? That was not me.
I decided it was time to get out of my shell and learn how to dance without a script.</description></item><item><title>2023 Summary: Part 3</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-3/</guid><description>When I left off in part 2, I said I spent July circumnavigating the globe. Also, I mentioned that I had started studying Swahili.
Kenya Nairobi My group of Quakers (Baltimore Yearly Meeting) is associated with both Friends General Conference (more liberal, no pastors) and Friends United Meeting (often more conservative, usually pastors). Every 3 years, FUM has their triennial. Ok, that&amp;rsquo;s obvious in the name. Anyway, the largest group of FUM Quakers is in Kenya, and it was their turn to host.</description></item><item><title>2023 Summary: Part 2</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/2023-summary-part-2/</guid><description>In May, I went up to Pittsburgh for Mothers&amp;rsquo; Day weekend. My brother&amp;rsquo;s New Zealand work visa had come through, so he was saying goodbye to the family.
Exam results In June, I got the notification that I had passed my DELE exam. Woot!
The breakdown on scoring is a maximum of 25 points each for reading comprehension, writing skill, listening comprehension, and vocal interaction. You need 30 points total between reading and writing and again between listening and speaking.</description></item><item><title>Things your Spanish teacher didn't tell you</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/things-your-spanish-teacher-didnt-tell-you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 22:54:19 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/things-your-spanish-teacher-didnt-tell-you/</guid><description>A friend of mine (a native Spanish speaker) just started teaching one of his friends Spanish, and the first thing I said was:
Explain to her that ser is essence/identity/characteristic and estar is status, and that’ll go SO much better than the “ser is permanent and estar is temporary” that makes us try to say “es muerto” and “estoy bautista” (because hey, conversion exists). Like, death is pretty permanent, but it’s still a status.</description></item><item><title>Bulk Delete Twitter Messages</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/bulk-delete-twitter-messages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 23:43:37 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/bulk-delete-twitter-messages/</guid><description><![CDATA[Hey, are you leaving Twitter? Are you worried that with 80% of the staff gone, it&rsquo;s just a matter of time until there start being unreported breaches? (Heck, maybe there have already!) Want to ensure anyone breaking into your account doesn&rsquo;t read your messages? Have a bulk-delete script, on the house!
To use this, go to the messages page on a computer. Right click somewhere on the page, and choose &ldquo;inspect&rdquo; (Chrome) or &ldquo;inspect element&rdquo; (Firefox) to get the developer tools to come up.]]></description></item><item><title>Well, that's a Friday</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/well-thats-a-friday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:09:29 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/well-thats-a-friday/</guid><description>This past Friday, I spoke at Code Beam America, and The Quaker World was published.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t spoken at many conferences in the last decade. I did the Elixir Wizards one virtually last year, and this is the first time in person since 2011.
It&amp;rsquo;s just a surprising coincidence that the book was published the same day. I wrote that chapter two years ago!</description></item><item><title>Tips &amp; Tools for Learning Spanish</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/tips-tools-learning-spanish/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 10:54:40 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/tips-tools-learning-spanish/</guid><description><![CDATA[[updated 2023-01-28]
I&rsquo;ve studied a silly number of languages in my life, starting with Spanish from age 6 to 14. I returned to studying Spanish in 2017, when I was working with an Argentine client. We spoke primarily in English (I was far too rusty for the alternative), but I quickly became frustrated with not knowing how to speak in the past tense in Spanish. I hurriedly crammed &ldquo;yo &hellip;é, tú &hellip;aste, él &hellip;ó&rdquo; into my head and tried to keep up.]]></description></item><item><title>Byzantine Easter</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/byzantine-easter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 08:34:55 -0400</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/byzantine-easter/</guid><description>Like much of Pittsburgh, I am ethnically Rusyn. I was raised mostly Roman Catholic (because my dad is). At Easter, though, I always attended Holy Ghost Byzantine Catholic Church, where my mom&amp;rsquo;s family belongs.
Byzantine Catholics have very different Easter traditions than many other Christians, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice until I experienced culture shock the time we took our basket to be blessed at the Roman Catholic parish where I grew up, and my basket was decidedly different from the others.</description></item></channel></rss>