<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>quakers - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/quakers/</link><description>quakers - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:09:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/quakers/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Well, that's a Friday</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/well-thats-a-friday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:09:29 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/well-thats-a-friday/</guid><description>This past Friday, I spoke at Code Beam America, and The Quaker World was published.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t spoken at many conferences in the last decade. I did the Elixir Wizards one virtually last year, and this is the first time in person since 2011.
It&amp;rsquo;s just a surprising coincidence that the book was published the same day. I wrote that chapter two years ago!</description></item><item><title>Quakers &amp; Forced Assimilation of Native Americans</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/quakers-forced-assimilation-native-americans/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 09:19:28 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/quakers-forced-assimilation-native-americans/</guid><description>Quakers were heavily involved in the forced-assimilation of Native Americans.
Today, through the Friends Committee on National Legislation (the Quaker lobbyist), we advocate for Native rights and Native sovereignty. FCNL employs Portia Kay^nthos Skenandore-Wheelock, a member of the Oneida Nation to run its Native American Congressional Advocacy Program. It was previously run by Kerri Colfer of the Tlingit Nation, and before that Lacina Tangnaqudo Onco of the Shinnecock &amp;amp; Kiowa Nations.</description></item><item><title>Finding Quakers</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/finding-quakers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:35:47 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/finding-quakers/</guid><description><![CDATA[Trying to find Quakers near you? Try one of these links:
General Australia Canada Quaker Maps: Canada, UK, US United Kingdom United States Worldwide Note that the &ldquo;worldwide&rdquo; link also includes a way to register yourself as an &ldquo;isolated Friend&rdquo; if there&rsquo;s no meeting near you. With time, new meetings can form.
LGBTQ+ If you are concerned about LGBTQ+ affirmation, here are lists of meetings that have formally stated their affirming position.]]></description></item><item><title>Reading List: Intro to Quakers</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/reading-list-intro-quakers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 14:39:55 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/reading-list-intro-quakers/</guid><description>Just leaving this here as a reference.
Books Your local Faith &amp;amp; Practice Advices &amp;amp; Queries A Quaker Book of Wisdom An Introduction to Quakerism Living the Quaker Way Our Life is Love Pendle Hill pamphlets Why Friends are Friends The Cambridge Companion to Quakerism Fit for Freedom, Not for Friendship Face to Face: Early Quaker Encounters with the Bible A Long Road: How Quakers Made Sense of God and the Bible Barclay&amp;rsquo;s Apology original or modern English Online Friends Journal Quaker Speak Quakers on Reddit Quakers on Discord Quakers on Twitter My podcast</description></item><item><title>Reading List: Quakers and Race</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/reading-list-quakers-race/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 14:39:55 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/reading-list-quakers-race/</guid><description>North American Quakers&amp;rsquo; history with racism is often whitewashed. Here are some links for a fuller picture.
Slavery in the Quaker World Quaker Indian Boarding Schools Fit for Freedom, Not for Friendship</description></item></channel></rss>