<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>tech - Category - Mackenzie Morgan</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/categories/tech/</link><description>tech - Category - Mackenzie Morgan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 21:09:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mackenzie.morgan.name/categories/tech/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advent of Code 2021</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/advent-of-code-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 21:09:29 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/advent-of-code-2021/</guid><description><![CDATA[In general, I regard myself as pretty bad at algorithms. I&rsquo;m comfortable enough doing the Elixir track on Exercism (that&rsquo;s how I learned Elixir), and I&rsquo;ve used HackerRank some, but the reason I used HackerRank was because TripleByte said algorithms were my weak point. (It said architecture was my strong suit, and I&rsquo;m quite pleased with that, as I did put effort into improving on that front.) I really dislike white boarding in job interviews (both because of the nerves factor and because the problems are usually totally unrelated to the job) and so much prefer take-homes.]]></description></item><item><title>Pretty Waterfalls in Honeycomb for an Absinthe app</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/pretty-waterfalls-in-honeycomb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 10:14:01 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/pretty-waterfalls-in-honeycomb/</guid><description>When first setting up the Absinthe app I work on, someone added OpenCensus Honeycomb package. The way it was set up was very basic: each top-level query had tracing attached.
:object queries do field :getStuff, :stuff do meta :trace, true arg :input, :string resolve &amp;amp;Resolver.stuff_resolver/3 end end This got us information on how long each query took, so we could see which query needed to be optimized and do some debugging when performance issues hit.</description></item><item><title>Reusable Django Admin Filters</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/reusable-django-admin-filters/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 14:14:01 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/reusable-django-admin-filters/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s fairly common to have a many-to-many connection to a User model. But sometimes, you have a lot of users in that table.
Problem 1: relations to large tables are unwieldy If we let the Django Admin load every single user into the dropdown in the Django Admin, it&amp;rsquo;s unusable. The dropdowns are too long. The page takes too long to load. We need to filter it in advance.
Dig around a bit online, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find some code of this form:</description></item><item><title>How to Network</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/how-to-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 04:39:51 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/how-to-network/</guid><description><![CDATA[Maybe you&rsquo;re about to graduate, just graduated, or have been teaching yourself to code for the last few years, and you don&rsquo;t know how to get your foot in the door with that first job. You see all those &ldquo;entry-level&rdquo; jobs that expect a year or three of experience. Networking is incredibly important, especially if you don&rsquo;t have any professional experience in the tech industry yet.
We&rsquo;ve all heard it: &ldquo;it&rsquo;s not what you know; it&rsquo;s who you know.]]></description></item><item><title>Elixir Wizards Talk: "Dealing With a Monster Ecto Query"</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/elixir-wizards-talk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:27:31 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/elixir-wizards-talk/</guid><description>Last month, I spoke at the first-ever Elixir Wizards Conference. It was a lightning talk walking through a refactor I did before the 2020 US Presidential Election, titled &amp;ldquo;Dealing With a Monster Ecto Query.&amp;rdquo;
I work for a news company, so the presidential election is a huge deal; we can&amp;rsquo;t have downtime. I knew which query was our bottleneck, so I optimized it right before the election. This took advantage of a few Elixir features, like atoms, the pin operator, and concurrency primitives.</description></item><item><title>Start of a List</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/start-of-a-list/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 22:16:01 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/start-of-a-list/</guid><description>Elixir has a lot of ways to get the first thing in a list. One of the first things you learn from the basic syntax guide on the Elixir website is that hd(foo) gets the first thing in a list, and tl(foo) gets the rest. You also learn [ head | tail ] = foo.
But what happens when it&amp;rsquo;s an empty list?
iex(1)&amp;gt; foo = [] [] iex(2)&amp;gt; hd(foo) ** (ArgumentError) argument error :erlang.</description></item><item><title>Dang, Elixir is stable</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/dang-elixir-is-stable/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 21:12:59 -0400</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/dang-elixir-is-stable/</guid><description>On Monday, my manager asked about on-call coverage for the Elixir app I work on. There are only a handful of people in the company who know Elixir, and he was concerned that I would feel like I couldn&amp;rsquo;t take a vacation.
Him: How often do you get on-call alerts?
Me: shrug Never 😏
Him: Wait, what? Do you have them set up? Do they work? 😰
Me: Yeah, they&amp;rsquo;re set up, and yes, they work, but the interval&amp;hellip;Two weeks ago, another team made a change that affected us without telling us, and that caused an alert.</description></item><item><title>Attending Code BEAM</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/attending-code-beam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:39:55 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/attending-code-beam/</guid><description><![CDATA[Last week, Miriam Pena from the Erlang Ecosystem Foundation&rsquo;s education working group mentioned in the Elixir Slack&rsquo;s channel for women and other minority genders that Code BEAM V America was coming up. She said the working group had a handful of tickets available for students, folks who can&rsquo;t otherwise afford to go, and people in groups that are underrepresented in tech.
I&rsquo;ve never applied for a &ldquo;diversity&rdquo; ticket to a conference before, but she said they&rsquo;d pre-purchased them, and the conference was 6 days away.]]></description></item><item><title>How's the Gender Ratio?</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/hows-the-gender-ratio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 10:54:40 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/hows-the-gender-ratio/</guid><description>I recently completed a job hunt. I was a lot more intentional this time about having a list of questions to ask the companies I was interviewing with. I highly recommend Key Values for generating a list of questions to ask. They explain why they&amp;rsquo;re worded the way they are, too.
I did ask one thing in a way they didn&amp;rsquo;t suggest, though. Diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI) is a hot topic, and I know that asking specifically with those words is likely to get me a canned answer.</description></item><item><title>Django Admin color picker</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/django-admin-color-picker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 03:09:31 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/django-admin-color-picker/</guid><description><![CDATA[When I add a new model to the Django app at work, I try to make sure the results in the Django admin have good usability, too. Just because it&rsquo;ll be mainly developers (and a few project managers) seeing it doesn&rsquo;t mean I can neglect usability. Consequently, I spend some time on hacking the Django admin. My manager says I&rsquo;ve been making it do things he didn&rsquo;t even realize were possible.]]></description></item></channel></rss>