<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Erlang - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/erlang/</link><description>Erlang - Tag - Mackenzie Morgan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 07:48:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mackenzie.morgan.name/tags/erlang/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>See you in New York</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/see-you-in-new-york/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 07:48:48 -0400</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/see-you-in-new-york/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://codebeamnyc.com/#schedule" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">schedule for Code BEAM Lite NYC</a> has been posted, and I&rsquo;m on it. I will be the first talk after the keynote, so that&rsquo;s exciting! I&rsquo;ll be doing a new talk this time, on adapting how you think about algorithms when shifting from an imperative programming mindset to a functional programming mindset.</p>
<p>This&rsquo;ll be my third time speaking at a Code BEAM event. Relatedly, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eMt_Wwp3N70" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">recording of my talk in Mexico City</a> has finally been uploaded to YouTube. Code BEAM recordings tend to be posted shortly before the following conference of a similar type (ie, that was a Code BEAM Lite and this is a Code BEAM Lite), probably to build excitement for the next one. Unfortunately, the audio isn&rsquo;t great, but if you want to hear what I sounded like doing public speaking <em>in Spanish</em> a year and a half ago, there you go. In the Spanish version, I took into account feedback from when I did it in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-hcvGTwPLFI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">2022 in English</a>, adding a more substantial introduction.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Well, that's a Friday</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/well-thats-a-friday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:09:29 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/well-thats-a-friday/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This past Friday, I spoke at <a href="https://codebeamamerica.com/talks/typing-with-pixie-dust/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Code Beam America</a>, and <a href="https://www.routledge.com/The-Quaker-World/Daniels-Grant/p/book/9780367142513" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">The Quaker World</a> was published.</p>
<p>I haven&rsquo;t spoken at many conferences in the last decade. I did the Elixir Wizards one virtually last year, and this is the first time in person since 2011.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s just a surprising coincidence that the book was published the same day. I wrote that chapter <em>two years ago</em>!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Advent of Code 2021</title><link>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/advent-of-code-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 21:09:29 -0500</pubDate><author>Mackenzie Morgan</author><guid>https://mackenzie.morgan.name/posts/advent-of-code-2021/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In general, I regard myself as pretty bad at algorithms. I&rsquo;m comfortable enough doing <a href="https://exercism.org/tracks/elixir" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">the Elixir track on Exercism</a> (that&rsquo;s how I learned Elixir), and I&rsquo;ve used <a href="https://www.hackerrank.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">HackerRank</a> some, but the reason I used HackerRank was because <a href="https://triplebyte.com/candidates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">TripleByte</a> said algorithms were my weak point. (It said architecture was my strong suit, and I&rsquo;m quite pleased with that, as I did put effort into improving on that front.) I really dislike white boarding in job interviews (both because of the nerves factor and because the problems are usually totally unrelated to the job) and so much prefer take-homes.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>